<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Solutions-Architect-Associates on TMK</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/</link><description>Recent content in Solutions-Architect-Associates on TMK</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Amazon API Gateway</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-api-gateway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-api-gateway/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon API Gateway is a fully managed service that makes it easy to create, publish, maintain, monitor, and secure APIs at any scale. With API Gateway, you can create REST APIs that access data, applications, and services hosted on AWS or on-premises. API Gateway also provides a variety of features to help you manage your APIs, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API authorization and authentication:&lt;/strong&gt; You can use API Gateway to authorize and authenticate users of your APIs using a variety of methods, including AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) roles, Amazon Cognito user pools, and OAuth 2.0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; API Gateway provides detailed metrics (CloudWatch) and logs (CloudWatch Logs, X-Ray) for your APIs, so you can monitor their performance and identify any issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API caching:&lt;/strong&gt; API Gateway can cache responses to your APIs, which can improve performance and reduce the load on your backend systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;API versioning:&lt;/strong&gt; API Gateway supports API versioning and stages, so you can create new versions of your APIs without breaking existing clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usage Plans:&lt;/strong&gt; Control access to your APIs and throttle requests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS WAF Integration:&lt;/strong&gt; Protect your APIs from common web exploits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about API Gateway that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Aurora</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-aurora/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-aurora/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Aurora is a relational database service that combines the performance and availability of high-end commercial databases with the simplicity and cost-effectiveness of open source databases. Aurora is MySQL and PostgreSQL compatible, so developers can use existing code, skills, and tools to build new applications, or migrate existing applications to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Aurora that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon CloudWatch</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-cloudwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-cloudwatch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon CloudWatch is a monitoring and observability service that provides data and insights in logs, metrics, and events. It collects metrics and logs from all your AWS services, and you can monitor them, visualize the data, and act automatically to changes in these services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about CloudWatch that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch collects and monitors metrics, logs, and events from all AWS services and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch metrics are numerical values that measure the performance of your AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch logs are text files that contain information about the events that occur in your AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch events are notifications that are generated by AWS services and resources when certain events occur.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch dashboards allow you to visualize your metrics, logs, and events in real time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudWatch alarms allow you to be notified when certain conditions are met.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details about CloudWatch that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Cognito</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-cognito/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-cognito/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Cognito is a fully managed user identity and access management (IAM) service that allows you to easily add user authentication, authorization, and management to your web and mobile applications. Cognito provides features such as user registration, sign-in, sign-out, password recovery, and access control, so you can focus on building great user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognito can be used to authenticate users with a variety of methods, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Username and password&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social login&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., Facebook, Google, Amazon, Apple)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-factor authentication (MFA)&lt;/strong&gt; with SMS or TOTP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom authentication schemes&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g., using AWS Lambda)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SAML and OIDC federation&lt;/strong&gt; for enterprise identities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cognito can also be used to authorize users to access your resources. For example, you can use Cognito to create user groups and roles, and then assign permissions to those groups and roles. This allows you to control who has access to what resources in your application. Cognito integrates with AWS IAM for fine-grained access control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon DynamoDB</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-dynamodb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-dynamodb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon DynamoDB is a fully managed, multi-region, multi-master, durable NoSQL database with built-in security, backup and restore, and in-memory caching for internet-scale applications. DynamoDB provides single-digit millisecond performance at any scale. It&amp;rsquo;s a flexible and scalable database that can be used for a wide range of workloads, including mobile, web, gaming, ad tech, IoT, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about DynamoDB that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Block Store (EBS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-block-store-ebs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-block-store-ebs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Elastic Block Store (EBS) is a block-level storage service designed for use with Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) instances. EBS volumes provide persistent storage for applications running on EC2 instances. EBS volumes are replicated within the Availability Zone in which they are created to protect against data loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EBS volumes are available in five volume types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General Purpose SSD (gp3):&lt;/strong&gt; Recommended for most workloads. Baseline 3,000 IOPS and 125 MB/s throughput, scalable to 16,000 IOPS and 1,000 MB/s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Provisioned IOPS SSD (io2 Block Express):&lt;/strong&gt; Highest performance SSD for mission-critical applications. Supports up to 256,000 IOPS and 4,000 MB/s throughput per volume. Supports Multi-Attach.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Throughput Optimized HDD (st1):&lt;/strong&gt; Cost-effective for frequently accessed, throughput-intensive workloads like big data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold HDD (sc1):&lt;/strong&gt; Lowest cost HDD for less frequently accessed workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;io1 (Legacy):&lt;/strong&gt; Previous generation Provisioned IOPS SSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gp2 (Legacy):&lt;/strong&gt; Previous generation General Purpose SSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EBS Snapshots Archive:&lt;/strong&gt; Cost-effective long-term storage for EBS snapshots.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EBS volumes can be attached to EC2 instances at any time, and they can be resized up or down without downtime. EBS volumes can also be used to create snapshots, which are point-in-time copies of an EBS volume. Snapshots can be used to create new EBS volumes, or to restore an EBS volume to a previous state.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-compute-cloud-ec2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-compute-cloud-ec2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon EC2 provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud. Key exam concepts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instance Types&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Purpose (M7g, T4g, M7i, T3, M7a, M7gd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute Optimized (C7g, C7i, C7a, C7gd)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory Optimized (R7iz, X2idn, X2iedn, R7a, R7g, U7i family, I7i, I7ie)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerated Computing (P4d, G5, VT1, P5en, Trn2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Storage Optimized (Im4gn, Is4gen, I4i)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Models&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On-Demand (short-term needs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Savings Plans (1-3 year commitment, restricted to single end customer usage from June 1, 2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spot Instances (up to 90% discount)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reserved Instances (capacity reservation, restricted to single end customer usage from June 1, 2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated Hosts (physical servers for your use)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dedicated Instances (EC2 instances on single-tenant hardware)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Capacity Reservations (reserve EC2 capacity for any duration)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Features&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Container Registry (ECR)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-container-registry-ecr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-container-registry-ecr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon ECR is a fully managed container registry that makes it easy to store, manage, and deploy Docker container images and Open Container Initiative (OCI) compatible artifacts. ECR is integrated with Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS) and Amazon Kubernetes Service (EKS), so you can easily deploy your containerized applications to production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon ECR that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Container Service (ECS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-container-service-ecs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-container-service-ecs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon ECS is a highly scalable, high-performance container orchestration service that supports Docker containers. ECS enables you to easily deploy, manage, and scale containerized applications. ECS provides a variety of features to help you manage your containerized applications, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Service discovery:&lt;/strong&gt; ECS automatically discovers and registers your containers, so you can easily access them from your application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Load balancing:&lt;/strong&gt; ECS automatically distributes traffic across your containers, so you can ensure that your application is highly available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Health monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; ECS monitors the health of your containers and automatically restarts any unhealthy containers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto scaling:&lt;/strong&gt; ECS can automatically scale your containers up or down based on demand, so you can ensure that your application has the resources it needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon ECS that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic File System (EFS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-file-system-efs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-file-system-efs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Elastic File System (EFS) is a cloud-based, elastic file system that provides a simple, scalable, and durable way to share files across multiple Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2) instances and on-premises servers. EFS is a fully managed service, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about provisioning, managing, or scaling your storage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EFS file systems are highly available and durable, and they can scale to petabytes of data. EFS also provides strong consistency and file locking, making it a good choice for a wide range of workloads, including web applications, content management systems, and databases.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-kubernetes-service-eks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-kubernetes-service-eks/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon EKS is a fully managed Kubernetes service that makes it easy to deploy, manage, and scale Kubernetes applications on AWS. EKS provides Kubernetes worker nodes, while the control plane is managed by AWS. EKS also provides a variety of features to help you manage your Kubernetes applications, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kubernetes orchestration:&lt;/strong&gt; EKS automatically provisions and manages Kubernetes clusters, so you can focus on building and running your applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security:&lt;/strong&gt; EKS provides a variety of security features to help you protect your Kubernetes applications, including encryption, authentication, and authorization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Load balancing:&lt;/strong&gt; EKS provides load balancing for your Kubernetes applications, so you can ensure that your applications are highly available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitoring:&lt;/strong&gt; EKS provides monitoring for your Kubernetes applications, so you can track the health and performance of your applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon EKS that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Elastic Load Balancing (ELB)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-load-balancing-elb/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-elastic-load-balancing-elb/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Elastic Load Balancing (ELB) is a load balancing service that automatically distributes incoming traffic across multiple targets, such as EC2 instances, containers, and IP addresses, in one or more Availability Zones. It monitors the health of its registered targets and ensures that traffic is routed only to the healthy targets. ELB scales your load balancer capacity automatically in response to changes in incoming traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon ELB that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon EventBridge</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-eventbridge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon EventBridge is a serverless event bus that makes it easy to connect applications together using events. It allows you to decouple and scale microservices, serverless applications, and legacy applications. EventBridge can detect events from a variety of sources, including AWS services, applications, and connected devices. It can then route those events to targets such as AWS Lambda functions, Step Functions state machines, Kinesis streams, and Amazon SNS topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon EventBridge that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon GuardDuty</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-guardduty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-guardduty/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon GuardDuty is a threat detection service that uses machine learning to analyze and identify malicious activity in your AWS accounts and workloads. GuardDuty monitors a variety of data sources, including AWS CloudTrail logs, Amazon S3 events, and Amazon VPC flow logs, for signs of suspicious activity. When GuardDuty detects a potential threat, it generates a finding that you can review and investigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GuardDuty can help you identify a variety of threats, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Inspector</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-inspector/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-inspector/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Inspector is an automated security assessment service that helps you identify and remediate potential security vulnerabilities in your Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances and Amazon Elastic Container Service (Amazon ECS) containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspector uses a variety of assessment techniques, including static code analysis, dynamic analysis, and network analysis, to identify security vulnerabilities. Inspector also provides recommendations on how to remediate the vulnerabilities that it finds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspector is a valuable tool for improving the security of your AWS workloads. It is easy to use and it can help you identify and remediate security vulnerabilities that you may not be aware of.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Kinesis</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-kinesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-kinesis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Kinesis is a fully managed, scalable, real-time, data streaming service. It can continuously capture and process millions of records per second, making it ideal for a wide range of use cases, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IoT data processing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time analytics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log aggregation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kinesis consists of three core components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kinesis Data Streams:&lt;/strong&gt; This service captures and processes streaming data in real time. Data can be ingested into Kinesis Data Streams from a variety of sources, such as IoT devices, web applications, and server logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kinesis Data Firehose:&lt;/strong&gt; This service delivers streaming data to data lakes and analytics applications. Kinesis Data Firehose can transform and buffer data before delivering it to its destination, making it easy to integrate with a variety of data processing systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kinesis Data Analytics:&lt;/strong&gt; This service makes it easy to process streaming data using Apache Flink and Apache Spark. Kinesis Data Analytics provides a variety of built-in libraries and connectors, making it easy to get started with real-time data processing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon Kinesis that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Macie</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-macie/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-macie/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Macie is a data security service that uses machine learning to automatically discover, classify, and protect sensitive data in Amazon S3. Macie can help you to identify and protect a wide range of sensitive data types, including personally identifiable information (PII), financial data, intellectual property, and healthcare data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Macie uses a variety of techniques to discover and classify sensitive data, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Machine learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Macie uses machine learning to identify patterns in your data that are indicative of sensitive data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natural language processing:&lt;/strong&gt; Macie uses natural language processing to identify sensitive data in text fields, such as email messages and document files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regular expressions:&lt;/strong&gt; Macie uses regular expressions to identify sensitive data in specific formats, such as credit card numbers and social security numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once Macie has identified and classified sensitive data, it provides you with a variety of features to help you to protect it, including:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Redshift</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-redshift/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-redshift/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Redshift is a fully managed, petabyte-scale data warehouse service in the cloud. Redshift makes it simple and cost-effective to analyze all your data using standard SQL and existing BI tools. Redshift is up to 100 times faster than traditional data warehouses, and it offers a variety of features to help you analyze your data, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massively parallel processing (MPP):&lt;/strong&gt; Redshift uses MPP to distribute data across multiple compute nodes, allowing it to process large datasets quickly and efficiently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Columnar storage:&lt;/strong&gt; Redshift stores data in columns, which significantly improves performance for analytical queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advanced Query Optimizer:&lt;/strong&gt; Optimizes query execution plans for faster results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Materialized Views:&lt;/strong&gt; Pre-compute and store results of complex queries for faster access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concurrency Scaling:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically adds capacity to handle concurrent queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redshift ML:&lt;/strong&gt; Create, train, and deploy machine learning models directly from Redshift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SQL compatibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Redshift is compatible with standard SQL, so you can use existing BI tools to analyze your data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Redshift Serverless:&lt;/strong&gt; Run and scale data warehouse workloads without managing infrastructure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Redshift that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-relational-database-service-rds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-relational-database-service-rds/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS) is a managed database service that provides a relational database infrastructure for deploying, scaling, and managing relational databases in the cloud. RDS supports a variety of database engines, including MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server, and Amazon Aurora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about RDS that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDS is a fully managed service, so you don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about provisioning, managing, or scaling your database.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDS supports a variety of database engines, including MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server, Amazon Aurora, MariaDB, and SAP HANA.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDS provides high availability and durability for your databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDS offers a variety of features to help you secure your databases, including encryption, access control, auditing, and integration with AWS Secrets Manager.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RDS can be used to deploy a wide range of database workloads, including web applications, content management systems, and enterprise applications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details about RDS that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Route 53</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-route-53/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-route-53/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Route 53 is a highly scalable and available cloud Domain Name System (DNS) web service. It provides a reliable and secure way to route end users to internet applications by translating domain names, such as example.com, to the numeric IP addresses of the underlying infrastructure where the applications are hosted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon Route 53 that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-notification-service-sns/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-notification-service-sns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS) is a fully managed pub/sub messaging service that enables you to decouple microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications. SNS provides a simple, reliable, and scalable way to notify multiple subscribers about the availability of new data, such as messages in a queue or events in a database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon SNS that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-queue-service-sqs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-queue-service-sqs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Simple Queue Service (SQS) is a fully managed message queuing service that enables you to decouple and scale microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications. SQS offers a simple, reliable, and scalable way to decouple and scale distributed systems and microservices. It is a highly available, durable, and scalable hosted queue for storing messages as they travel between applications or microservices. SQS moves data between distributed application components and helps you decouple these components.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-storage-service-s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-simple-storage-service-s3/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon S3 is a highly scalable, durable, and available object storage service that is designed for storing and retrieving any amount of data, from anywhere on the web. S3 provides a secure, durable, and low-cost storage infrastructure to host your static websites, store data used by web services, mobile applications, backup and restore, archiving and disaster recovery, analytics, big data applications, and machine learning workloads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon S3 that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-virtual-private-cloud-vpc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/amazon-virtual-private-cloud-vpc/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) enables you to launch AWS resources into a logically isolated virtual network that you define. This virtual network closely resembles a traditional network that you&amp;rsquo;d operate in your own data center, with the benefits of using the scalable infrastructure of AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about Amazon VPC that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPC is a logically isolated virtual network that you define.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPC provides you with complete control over your virtual networking environment, including the selection of your own IP address range, creation of subnets, and configuration of route tables, network gateways (Internet Gateway, Virtual Private Gateway), and VPC Endpoints.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use both IPv4 and IPv6 for most resources in your VPC, supporting dual-stack configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VPC can be used to build a wide variety of networks, including public networks, private networks, and hybrid networks, with options for VPC Peering and Transit Gateway for inter-VPC connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details about Amazon VPC that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CloudFormation</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cloudformation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cloudformation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CloudFormation is a service that helps you model and set up your AWS infrastructure resources. CloudFormation allows you to use templates to define a collection of AWS resources and the dependencies between them. You can then deploy, update, or delete your infrastructure using a single CloudFormation template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation is a service that helps you model and set up your AWS infrastructure resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation uses templates to define a collection of AWS resources and the dependencies between them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation templates can be written in JSON or YAML.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation templates can be used to deploy, update, or delete your infrastructure in a controlled and repeatable manner.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation can be used to implement best practices, such as infrastructure as code and idempotency, and version control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation Drift Detection helps identify when your deployed stack configuration differs from its template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudFormation Hooks allow you to invoke custom logic before or after resource operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CloudTrail</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cloudtrail/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cloudtrail/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CloudTrail is a service that enables governance, compliance, operational auditing, and risk mitigation by capturing, logging, storing, and delivering event log files that record API calls made to your AWS account and your resources. With CloudTrail, you can track user activity and API usage across your AWS services and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudTrail is a fully managed service that continuously logs all API calls made to your AWS account and your resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudTrail logs can be delivered to Amazon S3 and Amazon CloudWatch Logs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudTrail logs can be used to track user activity, troubleshoot problems, and audit your AWS environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CloudTrail logs can be retained for up to two years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CodeBuild</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codebuild/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codebuild/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CodeBuild is a fully managed continuous integration service that automates the build, test, and packaging of your software. It scales with your needs and helps you to release high-quality software more quickly and reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeBuild works by building your code in a Docker container environment, executing the build commands that you specify in your buildspec file. The buildspec file is a YAML file that defines the steps that CodeBuild should take to build and test your code.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CodeCommit</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codecommit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codecommit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CodeCommit is a fully managed, highly scalable, secure source control service that hosts private Git repositories. CodeCommit makes it easy for teams to collaborate on code development and track changes over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeCommit is a fully managed service, so you don&amp;rsquo;t need to provision or manage any servers. CodeCommit also provides a variety of security features to help you protect your code, such as encryption at rest and in transit, and integration with AWS IAM for access control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CodeDeploy</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codedeploy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codedeploy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CodeDeploy is a deployment service that helps you automate application deployments to Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances, on-premises instances, serverless applications (AWS Lambda), and Amazon ECS/EKS container services. CodeDeploy makes it easy to reliably deploy code and infrastructure changes to your applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodeDeploy works by deploying your application code to a set of instances or serverless functions. CodeDeploy then routes traffic to the new deployments and monitors the deployment to ensure that it is successful, with options for automatic rollback.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS CodePipeline</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codepipeline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-codepipeline/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS CodePipeline is a continuous delivery service that helps you automate the release and deployment process for your applications. CodePipeline builds, tests, and deploys your code every time there is a change, so you can release new features more frequently and reliably.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodePipeline works by modeling and automating the steps required to release your software. You can create a pipeline that includes the following stages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source stage:&lt;/strong&gt; The source stage retrieves the code from your source code repository, such as AWS CodeCommit, GitHub, Bitbucket, or Amazon S3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build stage:&lt;/strong&gt; The build stage compiles, packages, and tests your code using services like AWS CodeBuild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Test stage:&lt;/strong&gt; (Optional) The test stage runs additional tests on your code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploy stage:&lt;/strong&gt; The deploy stage deploys your code to your production environment using services like AWS CodeDeploy, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, or AWS CloudFormation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CodePipeline can be integrated with a variety of AWS services, such as Amazon S3, Amazon Elastic Container Registry (ECR), AWS Lambda, and AWS CloudFormation. This allows you to use CodePipeline to automate the release and deployment process for a wide range of applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Core Services</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-core-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-core-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS core services are the foundation of the AWS cloud platform. They provide the basic building blocks for building, deploying, and managing cloud applications. Some of the most important core services include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (EC2):&lt;/strong&gt; A web service that provides secure, resizable compute capacity in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3):&lt;/strong&gt; An object storage service that offers industry-leading scalability, data availability, security, and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Relational Database Service (RDS):&lt;/strong&gt; A web service that makes it easy to set up, operate, and scale a relational database in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Cost Optimization Strategies</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cost-optimization-strategies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-cost-optimization-strategies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS cost optimization strategies help you reduce your AWS costs without sacrificing performance or reliability. Some of the most important cost optimization strategies include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Choose the right service for the job:&lt;/strong&gt; Select the most appropriate AWS service for your workload, considering its features, performance, and pricing model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right-size your resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Continuously analyze and adjust the size of your AWS resources (e.g., EC2 instances, RDS databases) to match your workload&amp;rsquo;s actual needs, avoiding over-provisioning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Utilize pricing models effectively:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Savings Plans:&lt;/strong&gt; Flexible pricing model offering significant savings (up to 72%) on EC2, Fargate, and Lambda usage in exchange for a 1-year or 3-year commitment to a consistent amount of compute usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reserved Instances (RIs):&lt;/strong&gt; Offer substantial discounts (up to 75%) compared to On-Demand pricing for a commitment to a specific instance type in a region for 1-year or 3-year terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spot Instances:&lt;/strong&gt; Leverage unused EC2 capacity at steep discounts (up to 90%) for fault-tolerant workloads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Cost Allocation Tags:&lt;/strong&gt; Tag your resources to categorize and track costs across different projects, departments, or environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor and Analyze Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Use AWS Cost Explorer, AWS Budgets, and AWS Organizations to visualize, manage, and forecast your spending, and identify cost optimization opportunities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automate Cost Control:&lt;/strong&gt; Implement automation for stopping idle resources, scaling down during off-peak hours, and deleting unneeded resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage Serverless Architectures:&lt;/strong&gt; Pay only for compute time consumed, eliminating idle capacity costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimize Data Transfer Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Design architectures to minimize data transfer across regions, Availability Zones, and to the internet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use AWS Compute Optimizer:&lt;/strong&gt; Get recommendations for right-sizing your compute resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use AWS Trusted Advisor:&lt;/strong&gt; Get recommendations for cost optimization, security, performance, fault tolerance, and service limits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider using cost-effective storage tiers for S3, such as S3 Glacier Flexible Retrieval and S3 Glacier Deep Archive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Deployment and Management Services</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-deployment-and-management-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-deployment-and-management-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS deployment and management services provide the tools you need to deploy, manage, and monitor your cloud applications. Some of the most important deployment and management services include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS CloudFormation:&lt;/strong&gt; A service that helps you define and deploy resources in AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS Systems Manager:&lt;/strong&gt; A collection of tools and services that help you manage your AWS infrastructure and applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AWS CodePipeline:&lt;/strong&gt; A continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD) service that helps you automate your software release process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Direct Connect</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-direct-connect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-direct-connect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Direct Connect is a dedicated network connection between your on-premises network and one of the AWS Direct Connect locations. It provides a secure, reliable, and high-performance connection to AWS. AWS Direct Connect can be used to connect to any AWS service, including Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, and Amazon RDS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about AWS Direct Connect that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS IAM Access Analyzer</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-iam-access-analyzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-iam-access-analyzer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS IAM Access Analyzer is a service that helps you identify, understand, and remediate potential security risks in your AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) policies. Access Analyzer uses graph analysis to analyze your IAM policies and identify potential security risks, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excessive permissions:&lt;/strong&gt; Access Analyzer can identify IAM policies that grant users or roles more permissions than they need.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unintended access:&lt;/strong&gt; Access Analyzer can identify IAM policies that grant users or roles access to resources that they should not have access to.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public access:&lt;/strong&gt; Access Analyzer can identify IAM policies that grant public access to resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access Analyzer also provides you with recommendations on how to remediate the security risks that it identifies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-identity-and-access-management-iam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-identity-and-access-management-iam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Identity and Access Management (IAM) is a web service that enables you to securely control access to AWS services and resources. Using IAM, you can create and manage AWS users and groups, and use permissions to allow and deny their access to AWS resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM is a fully managed service that enables you to securely control access to AWS services and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM uses users, groups, and roles to manage access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM uses identity-based policies (attached to users, groups, roles), resource-based policies (attached to resources like S3 buckets, SQS queues), and access control lists (ACLs) to manage access to AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM users are individual people who are authorized to use AWS services and resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM groups are collections of IAM users who are assigned the same permissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM roles are sets of permissions that can be assigned to IAM users or groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IAM permissions are actions that IAM users or groups are allowed to perform on AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Key Management Service (KMS)</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-key-management-service-kms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-key-management-service-kms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Key Management Service (KMS) is a managed service that makes it easy for you to create and control the cryptographic keys that are used to protect your data. KMS provides a range of features that make it easy to manage your keys securely, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key generation:&lt;/strong&gt; KMS can generate high-quality cryptographic keys for you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key storage:&lt;/strong&gt; KMS stores your keys in a highly secure environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key rotation:&lt;/strong&gt; KMS can rotate your keys on a regular basis to help protect them from compromise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key auditing:&lt;/strong&gt; KMS provides detailed auditing of all key operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Lambda</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-lambda/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-lambda/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Lambda is a serverless compute service that lets you run code without provisioning or managing servers. Lambda executes your code only when needed and scales automatically, so you can focus on your code and not on managing infrastructure. Lambda supports a variety of programming languages and runtimes (e.g., Node.js 22, Python 3.13, Java 21, .NET 9, Ruby 3.4, and custom runtimes for Go).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about AWS Lambda that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Networking and Security Services</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-networking-and-security-services/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-networking-and-security-services/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS networking and security services provide the tools you need to build and manage secure networks in the cloud. Some of the most important networking and security services include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Virtual Private Cloud (VPC):&lt;/strong&gt; A logically isolated section of the AWS cloud where you can launch AWS resources in a private network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon Simple Notification Service (SNS):&lt;/strong&gt; A web service that enables you to decouple microservices, distributed systems, and serverless applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Questions</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-questions/</guid><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-and-how-does-it-work" &gt;What is AWS and how does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-difference-between-ec2-and-lambda" &gt;Explain the difference between EC2 and Lambda.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-well-architected-framework" &gt;What is the AWS Well-Architected Framework?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-iam-identity-and-access-management" &gt;Describe AWS IAM (Identity and Access Management).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-difference-between-amazon-rds-and-amazon-dynamodb" &gt;What is the difference between Amazon RDS and Amazon DynamoDB?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-amazon-vpc-and-subnet" &gt;What are Amazon VPC and subnet?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-significance-of-an-aws-availability-zone" &gt;What is the significance of an AWS Availability Zone?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-what-an-s3-bucket-is" &gt;Explain what an S3 bucket is.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-cloudwatch-and-how-is-it-used" &gt;What is Amazon CloudWatch, and how is it used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#define-the-term-elastic-load-balancing-in-aws" &gt;Define the term &amp;ldquo;Elastic Load Balancing&amp;rdquo; in AWS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-elastic-beanstalk-and-how-does-it-work" &gt;What is Amazon Elastic Beanstalk, and how does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-use-cases-for-amazon-sns-and-amazon-sqs" &gt;Describe the use cases for Amazon SNS and Amazon SQS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-lambda-handle-concurrent-executions" &gt;How does AWS Lambda handle concurrent executions?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-aws-cloudformation-templates-and-how-do-they-work" &gt;What are AWS CloudFormation templates, and how do they work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-differences-between-amazon-s3-ebs-and-efs" &gt;Explain the differences between Amazon S3, EBS, and EFS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-secure-your-aws-resources-using-security-groups-and-nacls" &gt;How do you secure your AWS resources using Security Groups and NACLs?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-aurora-and-how-does-it-differ-from-other-databases" &gt;What is Amazon Aurora, and how does it differ from other databases?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-aws-global-accelerator-service" &gt;Describe the AWS Global Accelerator service.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-trusted-advisor" &gt;What is the AWS Trusted Advisor?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-handle-data-encryption-at-rest-and-in-transit" &gt;How does AWS handle data encryption at rest and in transit?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-significance-of-amazon-route-53" &gt;Explain the significance of Amazon Route 53.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-elasticache-and-how-does-it-improve-application-performance" &gt;What is Amazon ElastiCache, and how does it improve application performance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-scale-an-application-on-aws" &gt;How do you scale an application on AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-serverless-application-model-sam" &gt;What is the AWS Serverless Application Model (SAM)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-aws-elastic-container-service-ecs-and-kubernetes" &gt;Explain AWS Elastic Container Service (ECS) and Kubernetes.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-features-of-amazon-redshift" &gt;Describe the features of Amazon Redshift.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-step-functions-work-and-what-are-its-use-cases" &gt;How does AWS Step Functions work, and what are its use cases?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-lambda-layers" &gt;What is AWS Lambda Layers?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-migrate-an-on-premises-database-to-aws" &gt;How do you migrate an on-premises database to AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-use-of-aws-direct-connect" &gt;Explain the use of AWS Direct Connect.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-elastic-file-system-efs" &gt;What is AWS Elastic File System (EFS)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-benefits-of-using-aws-cloudtrail" &gt;Describe the benefits of using AWS CloudTrail.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-elastic-load-balancing-elb" &gt;What is AWS Elastic Load Balancing (ELB)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-optimize-costs-in-aws" &gt;How do you optimize costs in AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-aws-organizations-and-how-are-they-used" &gt;What are AWS Organizations, and how are they used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-benefits-of-using-aws-fargate" &gt;Explain the benefits of using AWS Fargate.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-monitor-aws-resources-using-cloudwatch-alarms" &gt;How do you monitor AWS resources using CloudWatch Alarms?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-snowball-service-and-when-is-it-used" &gt;What is the AWS Snowball service, and when is it used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-codepipeline-and-its-components" &gt;Describe AWS CodePipeline and its components.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-datasync-and-how-does-it-work" &gt;What is AWS DataSync, and how does it work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-concept-of-aws-auto-scaling" &gt;Explain the concept of AWS Auto Scaling.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-set-up-aws-cross-region-replication-for-s3" &gt;How do you set up AWS Cross-Region Replication for S3?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-inspector-and-how-does-it-enhance-security" &gt;What is AWS Inspector, and how does it enhance security?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-app-runner-and-its-use-cases" &gt;Describe AWS App Runner and its use cases.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-back-up-and-restore-aws-rds-databases" &gt;How do you back up and restore AWS RDS databases?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-s3-select" &gt;What is Amazon S3 Select?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-features-of-amazon-eks-elastic-kubernetes-service" &gt;Explain the features of Amazon EKS (Elastic Kubernetes Service).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-deploy-a-serverless-application-using-aws-sam" &gt;How do you deploy a serverless application using AWS SAM?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-key-management-service-kms-and-its-role-in-encryption" &gt;Describe AWS Key Management Service (KMS) and its role in encryption.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-lambda-dead-letter-queue-dlq" &gt;What is the AWS Lambda Dead Letter Queue (DLQ)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-waf-web-application-firewall-work" &gt;How does AWS WAF (Web Application Firewall) work?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-glue-and-how-is-it-used-for-data-transformation" &gt;What is AWS Glue, and how is it used for data transformation?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-aws-shield-and-its-role-in-ddos-protection" &gt;Explain AWS Shield and its role in DDoS protection.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-codecommit-codebuild-and-codedeploy" &gt;Describe AWS CodeCommit, CodeBuild, and CodeDeploy.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-implement-disaster-recovery-in-aws" &gt;How do you implement disaster recovery in AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-cognito-and-how-is-it-used-for-user-authentication" &gt;What is Amazon Cognito, and how is it used for user authentication?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-create-a-custom-amazon-machine-image-ami" &gt;How do you create a custom Amazon Machine Image (AMI)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-concept-of-aws-transit-gateway" &gt;Explain the concept of AWS Transit Gateway.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-x-ray-and-how-does-it-help-in-application-tracing" &gt;What is AWS X-Ray, and how does it help in application tracing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-optimize-an-aws-s3-bucket-for-cost-and-performance" &gt;How do you optimize an AWS S3 bucket for cost and performance?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-systems-manager-and-its-features" &gt;Describe AWS Systems Manager and its features.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-snowball-edge-device" &gt;What is the AWS Snowball Edge device?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-cloudfront-work-for-content-delivery" &gt;How does AWS CloudFront work for content delivery?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-aws-resource-groups-and-how-do-they-simplify-resource-management" &gt;What are AWS Resource Groups, and how do they simplify resource management?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-features-of-aws-step-functions" &gt;Explain the features of AWS Step Functions.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-difference-between-amazon-kinesis-data-streams-and-kinesis-firehose" &gt;What is the difference between Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Kinesis Firehose?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-implement-high-availability-in-aws" &gt;How do you implement high availability in AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-use-cases-for-aws-greengrass" &gt;Describe the use cases for AWS Greengrass.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-global-accelerator-and-when-is-it-used" &gt;What is AWS Global Accelerator, and when is it used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-secure-data-in-amazon-s3-buckets" &gt;How do you secure data in Amazon S3 buckets?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-concept-of-aws-elemental-mediaconvert" &gt;Explain the concept of AWS Elemental MediaConvert.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-documentdb-and-how-does-it-differ-from-mongodb" &gt;What is Amazon DocumentDB, and how does it differ from MongoDB?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-create-a-vpc-peering-connection-in-aws" &gt;How do you create a VPC peering connection in AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-features-of-aws-lambdaedge" &gt;Describe the features of AWS Lambda@Edge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-fargate-and-how-is-it-different-from-ecs" &gt;What is AWS Fargate and how is it different from ECS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-artifact-enhance-compliance-and-security" &gt;How does AWS Artifact enhance compliance and security?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-privatelink-and-how-does-it-improve-network-security" &gt;What is AWS PrivateLink, and how does it improve network security?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-use-of-aws-greengrass-core" &gt;Explain the use of AWS Greengrass Core.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-set-up-aws-single-sign-on-sso" &gt;How do you set up AWS Single Sign-On (SSO)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-cost-explorer-and-how-does-it-help-in-cost-analysis" &gt;What is AWS Cost Explorer, and how does it help in cost analysis?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-use-cases-for-aws-organizations" &gt;Describe the use cases for AWS Organizations.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-cdk-cloud-development-kit" &gt;What is the AWS CDK (Cloud Development Kit)?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-implement-cross-account-access-in-aws" &gt;How do you implement cross-account access in AWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-difference-between-amazon-kinesis-data-streams-and-kinesis-data-analytics" &gt;Explain the difference between Amazon Kinesis Data Streams and Kinesis Data Analytics.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-snowmobile-and-when-is-it-used" &gt;What is AWS Snowmobile, and when is it used?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-use-aws-elastic-beanstalk-with-docker-containers" &gt;How do you use AWS Elastic Beanstalk with Docker containers?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-features-of-aws-control-tower" &gt;Describe the features of AWS Control Tower.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-aws-partner-network-apn-and-how-does-it-support-customers" &gt;What is the AWS Partner Network (APN), and how does it support customers?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-configure-amazon-cloudfront-with-ssl" &gt;How do you configure Amazon CloudFront with SSL?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-opsworks-and-how-does-it-automate-infrastructure-management" &gt;What is AWS OpsWorks, and how does it automate infrastructure management?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-aws-elastic-transcoder-service" &gt;Explain the AWS Elastic Transcoder service.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-transit-gateway-network-manager" &gt;What is AWS Transit Gateway Network Manager?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-does-aws-privatelink-work-with-service-endpoints" &gt;How does AWS PrivateLink work with service endpoints?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-aws-dms-database-migration-service-and-its-use-cases" &gt;Describe AWS DMS (Database Migration Service) and its use cases.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-aws-chime-and-how-does-it-facilitate-video-conferencing" &gt;What is AWS Chime, and how does it facilitate video conferencing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-use-aws-organizations-to-consolidate-billing" &gt;How do you use AWS Organizations to consolidate billing?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-amazon-polly-and-how-does-it-convert-text-to-speech" &gt;What is Amazon Polly, and how does it convert text to speech?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-concept-of-aws-eventbridge" &gt;Explain the concept of AWS EventBridge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-use-aws-data-pipeline-for-data-integration" &gt;How do you use AWS Data Pipeline for data integration?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-features-of-aws-codeguru" &gt;Describe the features of AWS CodeGuru.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-aws-and-how-does-it-work"&gt;What is AWS and how does it work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AWS is a cloud computing platform that offers a broad set of global compute, storage, database, analytics, application, and deployment services that help organizations move faster, lower IT costs, and scale applications. AWS&amp;rsquo;s services are built to be scalable and reliable, and they can be accessed on demand from anywhere over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Security Hub</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-security-hub/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-security-hub/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Security Hub provides centralized security governance across AWS accounts with these key exam-relevant features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compliance Standards&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PCI DSS v4.0 (latest update)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AWS Foundational Security Best Practices (FSBP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIS AWS Foundations Benchmark&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NIST SP 800-53&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ISO 27001&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Findings Correlation&lt;/strong&gt;: Groups related findings from GuardDuty, Inspector, Macie, IAM Access Analyzer, and other integrated services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security Score&lt;/strong&gt;: Quantitative measure of compliance status and overall security posture.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Region/Account Aggregation&lt;/strong&gt;: Centralized view of security posture across multiple AWS accounts and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integration with AWS Organizations&lt;/strong&gt;: Manage security at scale across your organization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Custom Insights&lt;/strong&gt;: Create custom queries to identify specific security issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automated Remediation&lt;/strong&gt;: Integrate with AWS Systems Manager Automation and AWS Lambda for automated responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Step Functions</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-step-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-step-functions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Step Functions is a serverless workflow service that makes it easy to coordinate the execution of distributed applications and microservices. It allows you to define workflows as a series of steps, and then Step Functions will take care of executing those steps in the correct order, handling retries and errors automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about AWS Step Functions that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Systems Manager</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-systems-manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-systems-manager/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Systems Manager is a service that helps you manage and automate your AWS resources. Systems Manager provides a set of tools and capabilities that can be used to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deploy, manage, and configure applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automate operational tasks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect and analyze data from your infrastructure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond to events and alerts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information you will need to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Manager is a fully managed service that helps you manage and automate your AWS resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Manager provides a set of tools and capabilities that can be used to deploy, manage, and configure applications; automate operational tasks; collect and analyze data from your infrastructure; and respond to events and alerts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Systems Manager can be used to implement best practices, such as infrastructure as code, configuration management, and continuous integration and continuous delivery (CI/CD).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some additional details that you may want to know:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Transfer for SFTP</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-transfer-for-sftp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-transfer-for-sftp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AWS Transfer for SFTP is a managed service that makes it easy to transfer files over the Secure File Transfer Protocol (SFTP). It provides a secure and reliable way to transfer files between your on-premises systems and AWS storage services, such as Amazon S3 and Amazon Elastic File System (EFS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is some short information about AWS Transfer for SFTP that you will need to know to pass the AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate exam:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Well-Architected Framework</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-well-architected-framework/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/aws-well-architected-framework/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The AWS Well-Architected Framework is a set of guiding principles for designing and operating reliable, secure, efficient, and cost-effective cloud architectures. It consists of six pillars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Operational Excellence:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on running and monitoring systems to deliver business value and continuously improve supporting processes and procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on protecting information, systems, and assets while delivering business value through risk assessments and mitigation strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on the ability of a system to recover from infrastructure or service disruptions, dynamically acquire computing resources to meet demand, and mitigate disruptions such as misconfigurations or transient network issues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on using computing resources efficiently to meet system requirements and maintaining that efficiency as demand changes and technologies evolve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost Optimization:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on avoiding unnecessary costs. This includes understanding and controlling where money is being spent, selecting the most appropriate and right-sized resources, analyzing spend over time, and scaling to meet business needs without overspending.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sustainability:&lt;/strong&gt; Focuses on minimizing the environmental impacts of running cloud workloads. This includes a shared responsibility model for sustainability between AWS and the customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>General Questions</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/general-questions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/general-questions/</guid><description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-cloud-computing-and-what-are-its-key-characteristics" &gt;What is cloud computing, and what are its key characteristics?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-differences-between-iaas-paas-and-saas" &gt;Explain the differences between IaaS, PaaS, and SaaS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-the-major-cloud-service-providers-and-what-are-their-core-services" &gt;What are the major cloud service providers, and what are their core services?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#essential-components-of-a-cloud-architecture" &gt;Essential components of a cloud architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#virtualization-and-cloud-computing" &gt;Virtualization and cloud computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-scalability-and-its-benefits" &gt;Cloud scalability and its benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-security-and-common-challenges" &gt;Cloud security and common challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-the-difference-between-public-private-and-hybrid-clouds" &gt;What is the difference between public, private, and hybrid clouds?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-data-storage-options-and-their-use-cases" &gt;Cloud data storage options and their use cases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#ensuring-data-redundancy-and-disaster-recovery-in-the-cloud" &gt;Ensuring data redundancy and disaster recovery in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#advantages-of-serverless-computing-in-the-cloud" &gt;Advantages of serverless computing in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#components-of-a-cloud-network-architecture" &gt;Components of a cloud network architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-handle-data-migration-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to handle data migration in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-a-reverse-proxy-in-a-cloud-environment" &gt;Role of a reverse proxy in a cloud environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-data-warehousing" &gt;Principles of cloud data warehousing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-bursting-and-when-it-is-useful" &gt;Cloud bursting and when it is useful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-monitor-and-manage-cloud-resource-performance" &gt;How to monitor and manage cloud resource performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-a-content-delivery-network-cdn-in-cloud-content-delivery" &gt;Role of a Content Delivery Network (CDN) in cloud content delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#significance-of-cloud-monitoring-and-management-tools" &gt;Significance of cloud monitoring and management tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-auto-scaling-works-in-cloud-environments" &gt;How auto-scaling works in cloud environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-migration-strategy-and-how-to-plan-it" &gt;Cloud migration strategy and how to plan it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-load-balancers-in-the-cloud" &gt;Role of load balancers in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#managing-cloud-resources-using-automation" &gt;Managing cloud resources using automation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#multi-cloud-and-its-advantages-and-challenges" &gt;Multi-cloud and its advantages and challenges&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-microservices-architecture-in-the-cloud" &gt;Principles of microservices architecture in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-virtual-private-network-vpn" &gt;Cloud virtual private network (VPN)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-secure-cloud-based-applications-and-data" &gt;How do you secure cloud-based applications and data?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#explain-the-concept-of-cloud-networking-and-its-components" &gt;Explain the concept of cloud networking and its components.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-is-cloud-billing-and-cost-management" &gt;What is cloud billing and cost management?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-do-you-achieve-data-backup-and-recovery-in-the-cloud" &gt;How do you achieve data backup and recovery in the cloud?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#describe-the-use-of-cloud-based-databases" &gt;Describe the use of cloud-based databases.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#what-are-serverless-functions-and-when-do-you-use-them" &gt;What are serverless functions, and when do you use them?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-identity-and-access-management-iam-in-the-cloud" &gt;Role of Identity and Access Management (IAM) in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-application-programming-interface-api" &gt;Cloud application programming interface (API)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-troubleshoot-cloud-based-applications" &gt;How to troubleshoot cloud-based applications&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#serverless-computing-and-its-benefits" &gt;Serverless computing and its benefits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#components-of-a-cloud-network-architecture" &gt;Components of a cloud network architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-handle-data-migration-in-the-cloud-1" &gt;How to handle data migration in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-a-reverse-proxy-in-a-cloud-environment-1" &gt;Role of a reverse proxy in a cloud environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-data-warehousing-1" &gt;Principles of cloud data warehousing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-bursting-and-when-it-is-useful-1" &gt;Cloud bursting and when it is useful&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-monitor-and-manage-cloud-resource-performance-1" &gt;How to monitor and manage cloud resource performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-a-content-delivery-network-cdn-in-cloud-content-delivery-1" &gt;Role of a Content Delivery Network (CDN) in cloud content delivery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-containers-in-cloud-computing" &gt;Use of containers in cloud computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-ensure-data-encryption-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to ensure data encryption in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-security-alliance-csa" &gt;Cloud Security Alliance (CSA)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-disaster-recovery-in-the-cloud" &gt;Principles of disaster recovery in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-choose-the-right-cloud-service-model-for-a-project" &gt;How to choose the right cloud service model for a project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-application-architecture-pattern" &gt;Cloud application architecture pattern&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-serverless-databases-in-the-cloud" &gt;Use of serverless databases in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-implement-high-availability-in-a-cloud-infrastructure" &gt;How to implement high availability in a cloud infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-cloud-identity-and-access-management" &gt;Role of cloud identity and access management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#continuous-integration-and-continuous-deployment-cicd-in-the-cloud" &gt;Continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-achieve-data-replication-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to achieve data replication in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-dns-service-and-how-it-works" &gt;Cloud DNS service and how it works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#benefits-of-cloud-serverless-compute-platforms" &gt;Benefits of cloud serverless compute platforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-handle-cloud-storage-security-and-access-control" &gt;How to handle cloud storage security and access control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-architecture-diagram-and-its-importance" &gt;Cloud architecture diagram and its importance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-compliance-and-auditing" &gt;Principles of cloud compliance and auditing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-design-a-resilient-cloud-architecture" &gt;How to design a resilient cloud architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-cost-optimization-and-how-to-achieve-it" &gt;Cloud cost optimization and how to achieve it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-native-application-development" &gt;Use of cloud-native application development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-manage-cloud-resources-using-infrastructure-as-code-iac" &gt;How to manage cloud resources using Infrastructure as Code (IaC)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-native-container-orchestration-platform" &gt;Cloud-native container orchestration platform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-application-performance-tuning" &gt;Principles of cloud application performance tuning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-achieve-data-governance-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to achieve data governance in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-cloud-access-control-policies" &gt;Role of cloud access control policies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-based-message-queues" &gt;Use of cloud-based message queues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-design-a-cloud-data-warehouse" &gt;How to design a cloud data warehouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-backup-and-recovery-strategy" &gt;Cloud backup and recovery strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-load-balancing" &gt;Principles of cloud load balancing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-secure-data-transfer-in-a-cloud-environment" &gt;How to secure data transfer in a cloud environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-disaster-recovery-planning" &gt;Cloud disaster recovery planning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-api-gateways" &gt;Use of cloud API gateways&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-achieve-cloud-network-segmentation" &gt;How to achieve cloud network segmentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-a-cloud-management-console" &gt;Role of a cloud management console&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-data-archiving" &gt;Principles of cloud data archiving&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-manage-cloud-based-databases" &gt;How to manage cloud-based databases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-native-service-mesh" &gt;Cloud-native service mesh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-resource-tagging" &gt;Use of cloud resource tagging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-design-a-cloud-content-delivery-strategy" &gt;How to design a cloud content delivery strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-governance-and-policy-enforcement" &gt;Cloud governance and policy enforcement&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-application-scaling" &gt;Principles of cloud application scaling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-achieve-compliance-in-a-multi-cloud-environment" &gt;How to achieve compliance in a multi-cloud environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-cloud-encryption-at-rest-and-in-transit" &gt;Role of cloud encryption at rest and in transit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-based-data-lakes" &gt;Use of cloud-based data lakes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-resource-lifecycle-management" &gt;Cloud resource lifecycle management&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-security-incident-response-plan" &gt;Cloud security incident response plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-application-monitoring" &gt;Principles of cloud application monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-ensure-data-privacy-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to ensure data privacy in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-network-optimization" &gt;Cloud network optimization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#use-of-cloud-based-container-registries" &gt;Use of cloud-based container registries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-access-management-strategy" &gt;Cloud access management strategy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#cloud-disaster-recovery-testing-plan" &gt;Cloud disaster recovery testing plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#principles-of-cloud-application-logging" &gt;Principles of cloud application logging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#how-to-achieve-cost-transparency-in-the-cloud" &gt;How to achieve cost transparency in the cloud&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#role-of-cloud-compliance-reporting" &gt;Role of cloud compliance reporting&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="what-is-cloud-computing-and-what-are-its-key-characteristics"&gt;What is cloud computing, and what are its key characteristics?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cloud computing&lt;/strong&gt; is the on-demand delivery of computing servicesincluding servers, storage, databases, networking, software, analytics, intelligence, and moreover the Internet (&amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo;) to offer faster innovation, flexible resources, and economies of scale.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/overview/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/overview/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All content belongs to &lt;a href="https://github.com/sv222/AWS-Solutions-Architect-Associate-Exam-2025" target="_blank" &gt;Stanislav&lt;/a&gt;. This is only for my personal reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/_overview-services.jpg" alt="_overview-services.jpg"&gt;
&lt;img src="https://dumindu.github.io/tmk/solutions-architect-associate/_overview-map.png" alt="_overview-map.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>